Pham Anh Thu

■ thu.pa1506@gmail.com **□** (+84) 369 209 256 **⑤** live:ichigo2603 **in** /thu-pham-3a828724a

Professional Summary

Experienced developer with 5 years in the industry and high-level proficiency in the following languages: PHP, JavaScript / TypeScript, and Python. I also have experience working directly with clients, and participating in the entire project lifetime. My passion is exploring new technologies and bringing them to the real-world applications.

I want to have an opportunity to challenge myself with big projects and work with many talented people as well as an environment with long-term development potential.

EDUCATION

Hanoi University of Science and Technology

2015 - 2020

Information Technology

CPA: 3.11/4

MAIN SKILLS

Languages: HTML/CSS, Javascript/TypeScript, PHP, Shopify Liquid, Python

Databases: MySQL, MongoDB, PostgreSQL, Redis

Technologies / Frameworks / Libraries: Micro-services, Laravel, NodeJS, NestJS, ReactJS, React Native, NextJS,

Redux, Webpack, Bootstrap, TailwindCSS, jQuery, Shopify, Kafka

Tools: Git, AWS, Heroku, Google Cloud Plaform, Postman, Docker, Figma

Others: Analysis user needs, English (intermediately)

EXPERIENCE

Solis Lab Co., Ltd | Shopify Developer

Oct. 2023 – Present

- Build e-commerce stores with millions of views per month for well-known brands around the world. The main platform and technologies are Shopify, NodeJS, ReactJS
- Optimize page speed by improving LCP, FCP, blocking time,... of web page. Make website is more SEO-friendly and faster.
- Integrate third-party apps / services to e-commerce sites.
- Ensure website UI/UX is responsive and working on all devices, browsers and OS (iOS, Android, Windows)
- Follow Figma design and make perfect-pixel UI
- Maintain client's e-commerce theme and improve features.

Ai-pro Joint Stock Company (was spin-off from Aimenext) | Full-stack Developer

Oct. 2022 – Oct. 2023

- Maintain client's CRM system, included API for mobile app, admin dashboard which are built by Laravel.
- Develop backend and mobile apps by React Native for used cars management system. Deploy apps for both iOS and Android.
- Implement image editor and OCR (Optical Character Recognition) application on React Native

Aimenext Joint Stock Company | Full-stack Developer

Apr. 2021 - Oct. 2022

- Maintain web and API of client system that makes stock price forecasts using AI.
- Use the headless browser to crawl Japanese user's payment history data from e-commerce sites.
- Build Learning Management System for Japanese clients using ReactJS and NodeJS.
- Develop and maintain CRM systems for many clients from different businesses.
- Guide and review the intern developers in the company's projects.

CTC Hoang Van Joint Stock Company | Full-stack Developer

Jun. 2018 – Apr. 2021

- Re-build CRM software for a cloud hosting provider company.
- Develop module booking flight ticket and integrate VNPT Epay payment gateway in a online booking system.
- Build CRM for mobile app that connects jobs and workers, sharing machines and equipment in the construction industry. Integrate multiple third-party services: OneSignal, Pusher, OpenStreetMap,...
- Guide and review the intern developers in the company's projects.

Sellonboard | AWS, Nginx, Laravel, MySQL, Redis, Kafka, ReactJS, Ant Design | \ \Phi\ \text{Website}

Dec. 2021 – Present

- Analysis the user needs, participate to design databases and system of project.
- Implement micro-services architecture. Use Kafka to comunicate between services.
- Integrate multiple shipment services and payment gateways into one dashboard. Build a dashboard that merchants can manage orders, setup shipment services and payment gateways for their stores on Ecwid (Ecwid is an e-commerce platform).
- Build CRM for admin and merchants using ReactJS.
- Implement Ecwid SSO login, social authentication (Facebook, Google).
- Solve issues relating to the process synchronizing hundreds of thousands of orders from Ecwid.
- Deploy system to AWS EC2, configure RDS, SQS, Cloudwatch and S3 for project.
- Review code and guide the developers.

Lucy Folks | Shopify, NodeJS, TypeScript, ReactJS, TailwindCSS, HTML/CSS | ♠ Website

Apr. 2024 – Sep. 2024

- Build an e-commerce store by using Shopify and ReactJS for an Australian client.
- Develop a perfect-pixel theme from Figma design, using ReactJS and TailwindCSS. Ensure the layout is not broken and all functions are working on all browsers, devices and OS.
- Integrate third-party apps and APIs, such as wishlist app, newsletter app,... and update app style based on the store's style guide.
- Optimize page speed of almost all pages in the website by reducing LCP, FCP, total blocking time,...
- Review code and guide the intern developers.
- Take on the same role as above for most of the Shopify sites developed by Solislab.

Used Car Inspection | NodeJS, ReactJS, React Native, PostgreSQL

May. 2023 - Oct. 2023

- Participate to design database and system of project.
- Build feature for Ships management, Vehicle management (develop both APIs and UI for mobile app).
- Build mobile app feature that can capture images and videos which will be used to detect caution plates, barcodes, VIN numbers of used cars by AI-OCR system.

Jan. 2023 – May. 2023

- Maintain and develop new features for the CRM dashboard using Laravel. Using one CRM dashboard for multi-purpose websites / mobile apps.
- Optimize SQL query for some APIs, make API run faster.
- Improve UI/UX of CRM dashboard based on customer requirements.

Kaiho OCR | AWS, Google Cloud Platform, NodeJS, React Native, MongoDB | # Google Play Nov. 2022 – Oct. 2023

- Implement Youtube Data API to upload user videos to Youtube and send video links to system API.
- Solve issues relating to keeping same ratio of images when rotate device, compress image size and upload image to AWS S3.
- Build mobile apps that can capture images and videos which will be used to detect caution plates, barcodes, VIN numbers of used cars by AI-OCR system.
- Deploy the mobile app to both app store of 2 OS: iOS and Android.

Ripi English Flash Cards | AWS, NodeJS, NuxtJS (Vue), PostgreSQL | \(\bar{\pi} \) Website

Oct. 2021 – Mar. 2022

- Build a website that allow users learning English via flash cards.
- Participate to design database and system of project based on requirements from client.
- Make a CRM for system using Vue and Material UI.
- Optimize SQL query for get flash cards every day based on client's rules, for statistic purposes,...

Gdata CRM | NodeJS, ReactJS, MySQL

Nov. 2020 – Apr. 2021

- Participate to design database and system of project based on requirements from client.
- Build CRM to manage staffs, servers,... for a hosting provider company.
- Build a customer services site with features: manage hostings / servers, send and reply feedback,...
- Review code and guide the intern developers.

2stay | AWS, NextJS, ReactJS, NodeJS, Express, MySQL, MongoDB, Ant Design

- Oct. 2020 Dec. 2020
- Participate to design database and system of project based on requirements from client.
- Implement micro-services architecture.
- Make a CRM for system using ReactJS and Ant Design. Implement Google Map API in dashboard.
- Build flight booking module by getting data from external flight data API, data normalization and calculating prices for one-way and round-trip flights.
- Crawl Vietnamese places data from **foody.vn** and normalized to the project database. Build the service nearby places of specific accommodation.
- Integrate VNPT Epay payment gateway as main payment method in project.

Webuild | AWS, Google Cloud Plaform, NodeJS, Express, React Native, ReactJS, MongoDB Oct. 2019 - Sep. 2020

- Participate in all phases of the software development lifecycle, including design, development, testing, and deployment.
- Build API for system that connects jobs and construction workers nationwide.
- Make a CRM for system using ReactJS and Ant Design. Implement OpenStreetMap and Google Map API in dashboard.
- Listen to feedback from end-users, identify and fix bugs, and participate in troubleshooting technical issues.